LYMAN WONG WEB DEVELOPER

Contact

lymanwong.github.io

4 (415) 509-1409

y lyman_g_wong

in lymanwong

lymanwong

Education

San Francisco State University Bachelor of Arts Biology

Skills

SKILLS: HTML5, JavaScript, jQuery, WordPress, Git, Agile Development, Jira, Sass/Less, Heroku, Bootstrap, CSS

Volunteering

Millennium School Apprenticeship Program at Hack Aug. 2019 to Feb. 2020 Create curriculum and manage the Millennium Apprenticeship Program at Hack

Projects

Hack Computer Website Dec. 2019 to Current

NY Times API Book Search

Made with PHP, AJAX, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap and HTML/CSS

Pinteresting

A Pinterest clone made with Rails 4.2, PostgreSQL database, and image hosting using AWS.

My Angular Profile and Blog Site

My personal website made with Angular, jQuery, Bootstrap, HTML and CSS.

Summary

My goal is to leverage my 3+ years of client-facing experience, community management skills, and expertise with my 2+ years of Front-End experience in the tech industry into a full-time Front-End position where I can continue to learn and grow.

Employment

Hack Computer · Community Manager

- · Created MVP for Hack's web application
- Created Google Tag Manager triggers to monitor website interactions
- Used Git and Sublime Merge to deploy learning content
- Wrote teaching curriculum for the Web including Bootstrap and HTML/CSS Added responsive pages and updated content using the Shopify API
- Created responsive news feed using HTML5 and CSS
- Created responsive email templates on Mailchimp
- · Wrote blog content explaining JS concepts using Markdown/HTML
- UI/UX bug fixing
- Migrated website from Shopify to Wix
- Used Phabricator to track development tasks

Udacity · Student Experience Specialist ·

Jan. 2018 to Dec. 2018

Apr 2019 to Current

- Created School of Business Content Marketing site based on Sketch wireframes
- Worked closely with multiple stakeholders to design the website layout
- Updated and published Digital Marketing program content using Markdown and Coco
- · Refactored and run Python scripts for student enrollment verification
- Implemented Zapier tasks to increase team efficiency
- · Used Jira to manage development tasks

Freelance · Web Developer ·

Dec. 2018 to Feb. 2019

- Add new features or improve UX for Squarespace and Wordpress sites
- Created a Wordpress marketing site for GameWithMe
- Implemented an SEO plan for TasteWithKevin.com
- Built new pages and updated site content as needed for TasteWithKevin.com
- Provided UI/UX design guidance
- Investigate technologies/techniques and propose the best solutions
- · Light project management

LeEco US · Web Developer ·

July 2016 to July 2017

- Created multiple responsive LeEco.com and LeEco.com/Chinese pages from wireframes
- Built LeEco US and India WordPress sites from wireframes
- Integrated new company header, a footer with region selector, Google Analytics, Optimize, and Tag Manager
- · Improved UI/UX using vanilla JS and jQuery
- Updated site content, conducted cross-browser testing, and bug fixing
- Assisted Front-End team to build an internal tool using React Material UI
- Use Git (version control) and worked on 1-week sprints/Agile development

Phlint, Inc. · Front End Developer Intern ·

Oct. 2015 to Apr. 2016

- Created responsive splash and blog pages from wireframes
- Transformed static client-facing page to a responsive, mobile-friendly site
- Integrated Mixpanel, Google Analytics, a new Favicon, and a video modal
- Integrated MailChimp signup form into the footer and download page
- Updated site content for Phlint and partner sites using FTP
- Legacy JavaScript code optimization
- Perform cross-browser testing, debugging and bug fixing
- Worked closely with design and CEO to plan, define and implement website improvements